Neisser, Hans Phillip; Papers ger069
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Reprints & Book reviews, Undated; 2
  - Book Reviews, Undated; 2.2
    - 7) Dick, Ernest, Ph.D.The Problem of Interest in its relation to currency and debt. Seven essays. London 1929. Williams & Norgate. XV, 381 S. 18/, Review by H. Neisser. From: Sonderabzug aus dem "Weltwirtschaftlichen Archiv" 33.Bd. (1931 1), Heft I, Seiti 95, Undated
    - 8) Dr. J. Schumann, D ie Sekforenanalyse als Instrument konjunkturtheoretischer Untersuchungen (Frankfurter Wirtschafts - und Sozialwissenschaftliche Studien, Heft 6.) Duncker und Humbno, Berlin 1959. 120 S. Review by H. Neisser. from: Separatum Kyklas Fasc. 3, 1961
    - 9) Neisser, Dr. Hans:Der Tauschwert des Geldes. yena 1928, Gustav Fischer. 204 S. review by Siegfried Budge. From: Literatur Band 86. Heft-Nr.3, Undated
    - 10)La Monnaie. By Robert Mosse. Bilans de la Connaissance Economique. (Paris: Lib. Marcel Rivière et Cie. 1950. pp.205) from The American Economic Review, Undated
    - 11) and 12) Somary, Felix: Die Ursachen der Krise, Fübingen, Verlag von J.C.B. Mohr (Paul Siebeck). 1932. VII, 122 S. Brosch. RM. 4.20, geb. RM.6, Undated
      Derselbe: Krisenwende- Berlin, Verlag S. Fischer, 1932. 59S. RM.I Review by H. Neisser. from Archiv für Sozialwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik 68.Band/l.Heft/Oktober l932.
    - 13) Neisser, H. -Der Tauschwert des Geldes. Jena, Fischer, M.9, 1923
      Review by Jenny Griziohi Kretsctmat. From: Geornale Degli Economisti, E, Rivista Di Statistica Vol. IV, 1930.
    - 14) Neisser, Dr. Hans Der Fauschwert des Geldes. Jena 1928. Gustav Fischer VIII, 204 S. RM.9, Undated; 2 copies
      Reviewd by: Dr. Friedrich A. v. Hayek, Wier. From: Weltwirtschalftliches Archiv. 29.Band / Januar 1929 / Heft.1.
    - 15) Hayek, Friedrich A.Gibt es einen Widersinn des Sparens Weir 1931 Gustav Springer. V, 54's. RM. 3 - reviewed by: Privatdozent Dr. Hans Neisser, Kiel. from: Weltwirtschaftliches Archiv. 35 Band / Heft 1, Januar 1932
    - 16)Gold and Monetary Stabilization, Letures, on the Harris Foundation 1932. From: Weltwirstchaftlichens Archiv. 37. Band /Heft. 1, Januar 1933
      by Jacob Viner, Prof. of Economics, University of Chicago, Gottfried Haberler, Privatdozent, University of Vienna, H. Parker Willis, Prof. of Banking, Columbia Univ., Lionel D. Edie, John H. Williams, Prof. of Economics, Harvard University of Chicago 1932. The University of Chicago Press, XI, 1738. Reviewed by: Privatdozent Dr. Hans Neisser, Kiel.
    - 17) Lö sch, August.The Economics of Location. New Haven: Yale University Press. 1954. XXVIII & 520 pp. reviewed by H. Neisser From: Social Research, 1956 Spring
    - 18) "Deutschland und Frankreich". Thee Wirtschaft und ihre Politik 1923/24. Herausgegeben von R. Kuczynski. Berlin 1924, bei R.L. Prager. 411. Reviewed by H. Neisser, from:Die Gesellschaft - Internationale Revue Für Sozialismus und Politik Nummer 8.I. Jahrgang, 1924 November
    - 19) Baster, A. S. J.The Imperial Banks. London 1929 P.S. King and San, reviewed by Hans Neisser, source-unknown, Undated
    - 20) Geschichte der Wissenschaft. Encyklopädisches, Lehrbücher. Spezielle Theoretische Untersuchungen. Helander, Sven, Die Ausgangspunkte der Wirtschaftswissenschaft. Jena (Gustav Fischer) 1923 8. 122SS. Reviewed by Hans Neisser from: Uebersicht uber die neuesten Publikationen Deutschlands und des Auslandes, Undated
    - 21) Santos, Clemer: Kooperation der Not enbanklen als Mittel zur Rationalisierung der Wirtwirtschaft. Tubingen 1931 Verlag von J. C. B. Mohr (Baul V) and 116S, Undated
    - 21) Schleivt, Alexander: Die Kooperation der Not enbanken. Ball 1931, Werlag (S)elbeng Sonderabzug & Licontewhan- VIII und 176s, Undated; reprint
      Reviewed by Hans Neisser, from: Sonderabzug aus S(ch)mollers Fahrber(05) Für Gesetzgebung, Verwaltung und Volkswirtschaft im Deuts(05) Jahrgang 56 Heft II 1932
    - 22) A Supplementary Note to the Article: "The Static Theory of Aggregate Investment" by Hans Neisser, 1967
      Reprinted from: Weltwirschaftliches Archiv Band 99 Heft 1
    - 23) Hans Neisser On the Sociology of Knowledge, an Essay. Copyright - 1965, James H. Heineman, Inc., New York, N. Y., Undated